[{"question": "when did God create the heavens and the earth?", "answer": "In the beginning everything was created by God.", "verse": "Genesis 1:1", "keywords": "created god beginning"}, {"question": "what did God create in the beginning?", "answer": "God created all the the heavens and the earth in the beginning.", "verse": "Genesis 1:1", "keywords": "beginning god earth created heavens"}, {"question": "who created everything in the beginning?", "answer": "God created everything on earth and above the earth in the beginning.", "verse": "Genesis 1:1", "keywords": "created beginning god earth"}, {"question": "what was the earth like in the beginning?", "answer": "The earth was formless and empty.", "verse": "Genesis 1:2", "keywords": "formless earth"}, {"question": "was the Holy Spirit present on earth in the beginning?", "answer": "The spirit of God was hovering over the waters before the earth was ordered.", "verse": "Genesis 1:2", "keywords": "ordered spirit waters god earth hovering"}, {"question": "how did God create light?", "answer": "God spoke light into existence.", "verse": "Genesis 1:3", "keywords": "existence god light spoke"}, {"question": "how did God perceive light, after he created it?", "answer": "God saw it that light was good after he spoke it into existence.", "verse": "Genesis 1:4", "keywords": "light good god spoke saw existence"}, {"question": "where does it say that light is good?", "answer": "In Genesis chapter 1, verse 4, it is written that God saw that the light was good after he created it.", "verse": "Genesis 1:4", "keywords": "light written god good created genesis verse saw chapter"}, {"question": "what did God do on the first day of creation?", "answer": "God created light, and separated it from darkness. After evening and morning, the first day was complete.", "verse": "Genesis 1:5", "keywords": "light evening god day created morning separated complete darkness"}, {"question": "when did God name light \"day\" and darkness \"night\"?", "answer": "God named light \"day\" and darkness \"night\" on the first day creation, after he created light.", "verse": "Genesis 1:5", "keywords": "light god night creation day created named darkness"}, {"question": "when did God create light?", "answer": "God created light on the first day of creation.", "verse": "Genesis 1:5", "keywords": "light god creation day created"}, {"question": "how did God create the skies?", "answer": "And God said, \"Let there be vault between waters to separate waters from waters,\", so God made a space that is now the atmosphere.", "verse": "Genesis 1:6", "keywords": "separate atmosphere said god vault waters let space"}, {"question": "did God separate waters that were on top of waters when creating the skies?", "answer": "Yes, the bible says that to create the skies God separated the waters and put a vault between them.", "verse": "Genesis 1:7", "keywords": "skies god waters vault bible create separated says"}, {"question": "how do we know that the space God made between the waters was the sky?", "answer": "after God created the vault (expanse, space) between the waters above and below he called it sky.", "verse": "Genesis 1:7-Genesis 1:8", "keywords": "expanse sky god vault waters called created space"}, {"question": "what day did God create the sky on earth.", "answer": "God created the skies on earth on the second day of creation.", "verse": "Genesis 1:8", "keywords": "skies god creation earth day created second"}, {"question": "how did God create the land we walk on?", "answer": "On the third day of creation God commanded the waters be gathered to one place, and dry ground appeared.", "verse": "Genesis 1:9", "keywords": "appeared dry god waters place creation gathered day commanded ground"}, {"question": "did God name the land and sea?", "answer": "After creating dry ground, God named it \"land\", and after gathering the waters he called them \"seas\".", "verse": "Genesis 1:10", "keywords": "creating gathering land seas dry god waters called ground named"}, {"question": "how did God create plants and trees?", "answer": "God spoke, and commanded the dry land to produce vegetation.", "verse": "Genesis 1:11", "keywords": "land dry god spoke commanded vegetation produce"}, {"question": "how did the dry land respond to God's command to produce vegetation?", "answer": "When God commanded, the dry land responded by producing fruit bearing trees and vegetation that had seeds.  Creation always responds according to God's will and decrees.", "verse": "Genesis 1:11-Genesis 1:12", "keywords": "fruit trees land dry god producing bearing creation decrees responded commanded responds vegetation seeds according"}, {"question": "In what day did God create the skies, seas and vegetation?", "answer": "God created the skies along with the seas, dry land, and vegetation on the third day of creation.", "verse": "Genesis 1:9-Genesis 1:13", "keywords": "land skies seas dry god creation day created vegetation"}, {"question": "what was God's command for creating the sun and the moon.", "answer": "In Genesis chapter 1 verse 14 we find God's command for creating the sun and the moon.", "verse": "Genesis 1:14", "keywords": "creating moon sun god find genesis command verse chapter"}, {"question": "what is the purpose for the sun and moon.", "answer": "God's purpose for the sun and moon were and still are to bring light over the earth.", "verse": "Genesis 1:15-Genesis 1:18", "keywords": "purpose light moon sun god earth bring"}, {"question": "did God make the sun, moon and stars?", "answer": "God made the sun and moon to and stars, each with its purpose, to bring light to day time and night time. ", "verse": "Genesis 1:16", "keywords": "purpose light moon sun god night day stars bring time"}, {"question": "does God want to separate the light from darkness?", "answer": "In God's perfect creation, his will is to separate light from darkness.", "verse": "Genesis 1:18", "keywords": "separate light god perfect creation darkness"}, {"question": "when did God create the sun, moon and stars?", "answer": "God created the sun, moon and stars on the fourth day.", "verse": "Genesis 1:14-Genesis 1:19", "keywords": "moon sun god day created stars fourth"}, {"question": "what was God command to create fish and birds", "answer": "God's command to create fish and birds can be found in Genesis chapter 1 verse 20.", "verse": "Genesis 1:20", "keywords": "god genesis verse birds create command chapter fish found"}, {"question": "did God create the all the creatures in the sea, and all the creautres that fly?", "answer": "On the fifth day of creation God created all animals that live in the sea and all the animals that fly in the sky.", "verse": "Genesis 1:21", "keywords": "animals fifth sky god creation day created fly sea live"}, {"question": "did God bless the fish and birds?", "answer": "After creating all the creatures in the sea and all the creatures that fly in the sky he blessed them.  God commanded them to increase in number to fill the earth and sea.", "verse": "Genesis 1:23", "keywords": "creating sky god increase fill earth fly commanded blessed creatures number sea"}, {"question": "when did God create all the sea creatures and birds of the sky?", "answer": "God created all the sea creatures and the birds on the fifth day of creation.", "verse": "Genesis 1:23", "keywords": "fifth god creation day created birds creatures sea"}, {"question": "what was God command to create the walk on the ground?", "answer": "you can find God's command for the land to produce all the creatures that walk in the ground in the book of Genesis chapter 1 verse 25.", "verse": "Genesis 1:24", "keywords": "land god find creatures book genesis walk ground verse command chapter produce"}, {"question": "did God create the animals that walk on the land?", "answer": "God created all the animals of the land.", "verse": "Genesis 1:25", "keywords": "created land god animals"}, {"question": "did God create man according to his image?", "answer": "God declared man would be according to his likeness, and image.", "verse": "Genesis 1:26-Genesis 1:27, Genesis 5:1", "keywords": "likeness declared god image man according"}, {"question": "did God give mankind authority over all the animals?", "answer": "When creating mankind, God declared that they would rule over all fish, bird and animal that walked in the ground.", "verse": "Genesis 1:26", "keywords": "creating rule declared bird god animal mankind walked ground fish"}, {"question": "how many genders did God create for mankind?", "answer": "God created two genders for mankind, male and female.", "verse": "Genesis 1:27, Genesis 5:1", "keywords": "female god mankind created male genders"}, {"question": "does God want mankind to populate the earth?", "answer": "God commanded mankind to be fruitful, increase in number and populate the earth?", "verse": "Genesis 1:28, Genesis 9:1", "keywords": "populate god increase mankind earth commanded number fruitful"}, {"question": "did God intend mankind to rule over all the animals?", "answer": "When blessing mankind, God stated mankind should rule over all the animals in the world. He also put fear and terror of mankind over the animals, and put mankind's dominion over the animals of the earth.", "verse": "Genesis 1:28, Genesis 9:2", "keywords": "animals world terror rule fear god mankind earth stated blessing dominion"}, {"question": "what did God intend mankind to eat?", "answer": "God gave all the plants with seeds, and trees with fruit that have seeds as food for mankind. He also gave all the animals in the earth as food for mankind. ", "verse": "Genesis 1:29, Genesis 9:3", "keywords": "trees fruit animals plants god food mankind earth gave seeds"}, {"question": "Should people eat meat?", "answer": "God gave all the plants with seeds, and trees with fruit that have seeds as food for mankind. He also gave all the animals in the earth as food for mankind. But you cannot eat meat that still has blood in it.", "verse": "Genesis 1:29, Genesis 9:3-Genesis 9:4", "keywords": "trees fruit animals meat plants eat god food mankind earth blood gave seeds"}, {"question": "what did God intend all the animals in the earth to eat?", "answer": "God gave all green plant as food for all the animals on earth.", "verse": "Genesis 1:30", "keywords": "animals god food earth green plant gave"}, {"question": "when did God create mankind?", "answer": "God created mankind on the sixth day of creation.", "verse": "Genesis 1:26-Genesis 1:31", "keywords": "god creation mankind day created sixth"}, {"question": "when did God create all the animals that walk on land?", "answer": "God created all the animals that walk on the ground on the sixth day of creation, along with mankind.", "verse": "Genesis 1:24-Genesis 1:25, Genesis 1:31", "keywords": "animals god creation sixth day created mankind ground walk"}, {"question": "was creation ever completed?", "answer": "After the sixth day of creation, it the bible declares that everything was finished.", "verse": "Genesis 2:1", "keywords": "finished declares creation sixth day bible"}, {"question": "what was completed when God finished creation?", "answer": "All the heavens and the earth and all the hosts of them were completed", "verse": "Genesis 2:1", "keywords": "hosts earth completed heavens"}, {"question": "when did God rest after finishing all of creation?", "answer": "On the seventh day, good ended his work and rested.", "verse": "Genesis 2:2", "keywords": "work good ended day rested seventh"}, {"question": "how long did it take God to finish everything?", "answer": "It took God six days to finish the work of creation.", "verse": "Genesis 2:2", "keywords": "work took god creation days finish"}, {"question": "why is the seventh day considered holy?", "answer": "The seventh day is holy because God rested from all his work, and he blessed it and made it holy.", "verse": "Genesis 2:3", "keywords": "work holy god day blessed rested seventh"}, {"question": "how was the ground watered before man was created?", "answer": "Before God sent rain, the ground was watered by streams that rose from the ground.", "verse": "Genesis 2:5-Genesis 2:6", "keywords": "streams rose sent god rain ground watered"}, {"question": "what did God use to form man?", "answer": "God used the dust from the ground to form man.", "verse": "Genesis 2:7", "keywords": "god form ground dust man"}, {"question": "how did God form man?", "answer": "God took dust from the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life.", "verse": "Genesis 2:7", "keywords": "breath took god life ground nostrils dust breathed"}, {"question": "did God plant a garden in Eden?", "answer": "the Lord planted a garden in the east, in Eden.", "verse": "Genesis 2:8", "keywords": "eden garden planted east lord"}, {"question": "in what direction was the garden of Eden placed?", "answer": "the Lord planted the garden of Eden to the east.", "verse": "Genesis 2:8", "keywords": "eden garden planted east lord"}, {"question": "did God place man in the garden of Eden?", "answer": "God placed man in the garden of Eden?", "verse": "Genesis 2:8", "keywords": "eden god garden placed man"}, {"question": "what kind of trees did God put in the garden of Eden?", "answer": "God made all kinds of beautiful trees in the garden of Eden that were good for food.", "verse": "Genesis 2:9", "keywords": "trees beautiful eden god good food garden kinds"}, {"question": "what was in the middle of the garden of Eden?", "answer": "in the middle of the garden God placed the tree of life, and the tree of the knowledge of good and evil", "verse": "Genesis 2:9", "keywords": "tree middle evil god knowledge good life garden placed"}, {"question": "where is the tree of life located?", "answer": "The tree of life is located in the middle of the garden of Eden.", "verse": "Genesis 2:9", "keywords": "located tree middle eden life garden"}, {"question": "what is the tree of life?", "answer": "the tree of life is one of the two trees God placed in the middle of the garden of Eden.", "verse": "Genesis 2:9", "keywords": "trees tree middle eden god life garden placed"}, {"question": "what is the tree of knowledge of good and evil?", "answer": "the tree of life is one of the two trees God placed in the middle of the garden of Eden.", "verse": "Genesis 2:9", "keywords": "trees tree middle eden god life garden placed"}, {"question": "how was the garden of Eden watered?", "answer": "a river flowed from the garden of Eden and watered it.", "verse": "Genesis 2:10", "keywords": "eden garden river flowed watered"}, {"question": "did the river that watered the garden of Eden separate into other rivers?", "answer": "the river that watered the garden of Eden separated into four other rivers; they are Pishon, Gihon, Tigris and Euphrates.", "verse": "Genesis 2:10-Genesis 2:14", "keywords": "pishon rivers eden garden river tigris euphrates separated watered gihon"}, {"question": "what is the Pishon river?", "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the first is the Pishon river.", "verse": "Genesis 2:11", "keywords": "pishon rivers eden waters main garden river separates"}, {"question": "where does the Pishon river travel trough?", "answer": "The Pishon river travels through the entire land of Havilah.", "verse": "Genesis 2:11", "keywords": "pishon land river entire havilah travels"}, {"question": "is there gold iin Havilah?", "answer": "The gold in the land of Havilah is good, along with resin and onyx.", "verse": "Genesis 2:11-Genesis 2:12", "keywords": "land good gold havilah resin onyx"}, {"question": "What kind of natural resources are found in Havilah?", "answer": "Havilah has gold, resin and onyx of good quality.", "verse": "Genesis 2:11-Genesis 2:12", "keywords": "good gold quality havilah resin onyx"}, {"question": "what is the Gihon river?", "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the second is the Gihon river.", "verse": "Genesis 2:13", "keywords": "rivers eden waters main garden river second separates gihon"}, {"question": "where does the Gihon river travel through?", "answer": "The Gihon river travels through the entire land of Cush.", "verse": "Genesis 2:13", "keywords": "land river entire cush travels gihon"}, {"question": "what is the Tigris river?", "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the third is the Tigris river.", "verse": "Genesis 2:14", "keywords": "rivers eden waters main garden river tigris separates"}, {"question": "where does the Tigris river travel through?", "answer": "The Tigris river travels through the east side of Ashur.", "verse": "Genesis 2:14", "keywords": "ashur east tigris river travels"}, {"question": "What is the Euphrates river?", "answer": "When the river that waters the garden of Eden separates into four main rivers, the fourth is the Euphrates river.", "verse": "Genesis 2:14", "keywords": "rivers eden waters main garden river fourth euphrates separates"}, {"question": "Why did God put man in the garden of Eden?", "answer": "The Lord put man in the garden of Eden to work it and care for it.", "verse": "Genesis 2:15", "keywords": "work eden care garden man lord"}, {"question": "what did man eat in the garden of Eden?", "answer": "man was free to eat from any tree in the garden, except from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil. ", "verse": "Genesis 2:15", "keywords": "man tree eat evil knowledge good garden free"}, {"question": "what was man not allowed to eat in the garden of Eden?", "answer": "Man was not allowed to eat from the tree of knowledge of good and evil.", "verse": "Genesis 2:17", "keywords": "tree eat evil knowledge good allowed man"}, {"question": "was man allowed to eat from the tree of knowledge of good and evil?", "answer": "Man was not allowed to eat from the tree of knowledge of good and evil.", "verse": "Genesis 2:17", "keywords": "tree eat evil knowledge good allowed man"}, {"question": "what would happen to man if he ate from the fruit of the tree of knowledge of good and evil?", "answer": "God declared that if man ate from the fruit of the tree of knowledge of good and evil, he would certainly die. ", "verse": "Genesis 2:17", "keywords": "fruit die tree declared evil god knowledge good ate man"}, {"question": "does God want man to be alone?", "answer": "The Lord God said, \"It is not good for man to be alone.\"", "verse": "Genesis 2:18", "keywords": "said good god man lord"}, {"question": "what did God first do to aid mans' loneliness?", "answer": "God brought all the animals of the land and birds of the sky to Adam, so he could name them.", "verse": "Genesis 2:19", "keywords": "animals brought land adam sky god birds"}, {"question": "did Adam give names to all the animals?", "answer": "God gave Adam the task of naming all the animals.", "verse": "Genesis 2:19", "keywords": "animals adam god naming task gave"}, {"question": "was any suitable helper found within the animals for Adam?", "answer": "There was no suitable helper found in any animal.", "verse": "Genesis 2:20", "keywords": "suitable found animal helper"}, {"question": "how did God remove a rib from Adam?", "answer": "God made Adam fall into a deep sleep, and took a rib from him.", "verse": "Genesis 2:21", "keywords": "took adam god sleep deep fall rib"}, {"question": "what did God remove from Adam when he put him to sleep?", "answer": "God removed a rib from Adam after putting him in a deep sleep.", "verse": "Genesis 2:21", "keywords": "adam god putting sleep deep removed rib"}, {"question": "why did God remove a rib from Adam?", "answer": "God removed a rib from Adam to create a woman.", "verse": "Genesis 2:22", "keywords": "adam god woman removed create rib"}, {"question": "what did God create with Adam's rib?", "answer": "God used Adams's rib to create a women.", "verse": "Genesis 2:22", "keywords": "god adams women create rib"}, {"question": "what did adam say when he saw Eve?", "answer": "When Adam saw eve he said, \"This is now bone of my bone and flesh of my flesh.\" and named her women", "verse": "Genesis 2:23", "keywords": "bone said adam eve flesh women saw named"}, {"question": "Why does man leave his father and mother?", "answer": "Man will leave his father and mother to become one with his wife.", "verse": "{} 2:24", "keywords": "man father wife mother leave"}, {"question": "what happens when a man and a women unite?", "answer": "When a man and a women unite, they become one flesh.", "verse": "Genesis 2:24", "keywords": "unite man flesh women"}, {"question": "were Adam and Eve naked in the garden of Eden?", "answer": "Adam and Eve were naked in garden of Eden, but they were not ashamed.", "verse": "Genesis 2:25", "keywords": "ashamed adam eden eve naked garden"}, {"question": "was Adam and Eve ashamed of being naked in the garden of Eden?", "verse": "Even thou Adam and Eve were naked in the garden of Eden, they were not ashamed.", "answer": "Genesis 2:25", "keywords": "genesis"}, {"question": "who was the craftiest animal the Lord had made?", "answer": "Of all the animals, the serpent was the craftiest animal the Lord had made.", "verse": "Genesis 3:1", "keywords": "serpent animals animal craftiest lord"}, {"question": "did Eve know she was not suppose to eat the fruit of the three of knowledge of good and evil?", "answer": "Eve knew that they were not allowed to touch or eat of the tree that is in the middle of the garden.", "verse": "Genesis 3:2-Genesis 3:3", "keywords": "tree eat middle allowed eve garden touch knew"}, {"question": "how did the snake trick Eve into eating the fruit.", "answer": "The serpent told Eve that if they ate of the fruit of knowledge they would not die.", "verse": "Genesis 3:4", "keywords": "serpent fruit die told knowledge eve ate"}, {"question": "who did the snake trick into eating the fruit?", "answer": "The serpent tricked Eve into eating the fruit of knowledge of good and evil.", "verse": "Genesis 3:4", "keywords": "serpent fruit evil knowledge good eve tricked eating"}, {"question": "what would happen to Eve if she ate of the fruit of knowledge according to the snake?", "answer": "The snake said that she would not die, and she would be like God.", "verse": "Genesis 3:4-Genesis 3:5", "keywords": "die snake said god"}, {"question": "what did Eve see when she looked at the fruit of knowledge?", "answer": "Eve saw that fruit was pleasing to look at and desirable for gaining knowledge.", "verse": "Genesis 3:6", "keywords": "fruit gaining desirable knowledge look eve saw pleasing"}, {"question": "did Eve give to her husband Adam some of the fruit to eat?", "answer": "After eating of the fruit of knowledge, she gave some to her husband Adam.", "verse": "Genesis 3:6", "keywords": "fruit adam knowledge husband gave eating"}, {"question": "did Adam eat of the fruit of knowledge of good and evil?", "answer": "After Eve was tricked into eating of the fruit, she gave some to her husband Adam and he ate the fruit. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:6", "keywords": "fruit adam husband eve ate tricked gave eating"}, {"question": "what happened to Adam and Eve after they ate the fruit of knowledge of good and evil?", "answer": "After eating of the fruit of knowledge, both Adam and Eve's eyes were opened, and they realize they were naked. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:7", "keywords": "fruit realize adam knowledge eyes eve naked opened eating"}, {"question": "how did Adam and Eve realize that they were both naked?", "answer": "Adam and Eve both realized that they were naked after eating the fruit of the tree of knowledge that God had forbidden. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:6-Genesis 3:7", "keywords": "fruit tree adam forbidden knowledge god eve naked realized eating"}, {"question": "how did Adam and Eve cover themselves after they realized they were naked?", "answer": "After realizing they naked, Adam and Eve sowed fig leaves together to cover themselves.", "verse": "Genesis 3:7", "keywords": "cover adam fig realizing eve naked leaves sowed"}, {"question": "what did Adam and Eve use to cover themselves?", "answer": "Adam and Eve used fig leaves sewn together cover themselves. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:7", "keywords": "cover fig adam eve leaves sewn"}, {"question": "what did Adam and Eve hear after eating of the fruit of knowledge of good and evil?", "answer": "After eating of the fruit, Adam and Eve heard the Lord God walking in the garden in the cool of the day.", "verse": "Genesis 3:8", "keywords": "fruit heard walking adam god eve day garden eating lord cool"}, {"question": "what did Adam and Eve do when they heard the Lord God walking through the garden?", "answer": "When Adam and Eve heard the Lord God waling through the garden, they were afraid and hid among the trees. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:8", "keywords": "trees heard waling adam god eve garden hid afraid lord"}, {"question": "did the Lord God call out to Adam when he and his Eve hid from him??", "answer": "The Lord God called out to them when they were hiding from him in the trees of the garden.", "verse": "Genesis 3:9", "keywords": "trees god called garden hiding lord"}, {"question": "why did Adam hide from the Lord after he realized he was naked?", "answer": "Adam hid from the Lord after he realized he was naked because he was afraid?", "verse": "Genesis 3:10", "keywords": "adam naked hid realized afraid lord"}, {"question": "what was Adam afraid of when the Lord called out to him after Adam realized he was naked?", "answer": "The bible does not say what Adam was afraid of, when God called out to him.", "verse": "Genesis 3:10", "keywords": "adam god called bible afraid"}, {"question": "did God question Adam how he know he was naked?", "answer": "God asked Adam who had revealed to them that they were naked, and if he had eaten of the fruit of knowledge?", "verse": "Genesis 3:11", "keywords": "fruit revealed asked adam god knowledge naked eaten"}, {"question": "what was Adam's excuse to the Lord God on why he ate the fruit of knowledge?", "answer": "Adam blamed Eve for giving him some of the fruit to eat.", "verse": "Genesis 3:12", "keywords": "fruit eat adam eve giving blamed"}, {"question": "what was Eve's excuse to the Lord God on why she ate the fruit?", "answer": "Eve blamed the serpent for tricking her into eating of the fruit of knowledge.", "verse": "Genesis 3:13", "keywords": "serpent fruit knowledge eve eating blamed tricking"}, {"question": "what was God's curse to the serpent for tricking Eve into eating of the fruit of knowledge?", "answer": "God cursed the serpent above all animals, it would crawl on its belly and eat dust. God put hostility between man and serpent. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:14-Genesis 3:15", "keywords": "serpent belly animals eat god hostility cursed crawl dust man"}, {"question": "why did God curse the serpent?", "answer": "God cursed the serpent because it had tricked Eve into eating of the fruit of knowledge.", "verse": "Genesis 3:13-Genesis 3:15", "keywords": "serpent fruit god knowledge cursed eve tricked eating"}, {"question": "why did God curse Eve?", "answer": "God cursed Eve because she had eaten of the fruit of knowledge: God had forbidden Adam and Eve from eating of that fruit. ", "verse": "Genesis 2:17, Genesis 3:16", "keywords": "fruit adam forbidden god knowledge cursed eve eaten eating"}, {"question": "what was God's curse to Eve?", "answer": "God's curse to Eve was that giving birth would be severely painful, that her desire would be for her husband, and that her husband would rule over her. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:16", "keywords": "rule god desire husband curse eve painful giving birth"}, {"question": "why is giving birth so painful to a women?", "answer": "Giving birth is painful for a woman because it is God's decree over Eve for eating of the fruit of knowledge. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:16", "keywords": "decree fruit god knowledge eve woman painful giving eating birth"}, {"question": "what is a woman's desire?", "answer": "Decreed by God, a woman's desire is for her husband.", "verse": "Genesis 3:16", "keywords": "decreed god husband woman desire"}, {"question": "Is a husband suppose to rule over his wife?", "answer": "Decreed by God, a husband is to rule over his wife.", "verse": "Genesis 3:16", "keywords": "rule wife decreed god husband"}, {"question": "why did God curse Adam.", "answer": "God cursed Adam because he listened to his wife and ate from the tree of knowledge, which God had forbidden both from eating. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:17", "keywords": "tree wife adam forbidden god knowledge cursed ate listened eating"}, {"question": "what was Adam's curse.", "answer": "God decreed that Adam would have to work for his food, his work would be hard until he died; when he died he would return to the ground. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:17-Genesis 3:19", "keywords": "work died adam decreed god food ground hard return"}, {"question": "is the ground cursed because of Adam's sin?", "answer": "The ground was cursed because of Adam's sin, it now produces thorns and thistles.", "verse": "Genesis 3:17-Genesis 3:19", "keywords": "produces thistles adam sin thorns cursed ground"}, {"question": "how was mankind suppose to get food after the Lord God kicked them out of the garden?", "answer": "Through hard work, would mankind eat from the plants of thr ground.", "verse": "Genesis 3:17-Genesis 3-19", "keywords": "work plants eat thr mankind ground hard"}, {"question": "is man suppose to work hard?", "answer": "God sentenced man to work hard all his life until the day he dies.", "verse": "Genesis 3:17-Genesis 3-19", "keywords": "work dies god life day sentenced man"}, {"question": "is mankind suppose to die?", "answer": "All men will return to the dust he came from, this was declared by the Lord God.", "verse": "Genesis 3:19", "keywords": "declared god came return dust lord men"}, {"question": "did Adam name his wife \"Eve\"?", "answer": "Adam named his wife Eve because she would become the mother of all the people to come.", "verse": "Genesis 3:20", "keywords": "wife adam eve people come mother named"}, {"question": "is Eve the mother of all the people in the world?", "answer": "Since Eve is the first women, she is the mother of all the people who came after her.", "verse": "Genesis 3:20", "keywords": "eve came people women mother"}, {"question": "did the Lord God clothed Adam and Eve?", "answer": "The Lord made garments of skin for Adam and his wife and clothed them.", "verse": "Genesis 3:21", "keywords": "wife adam garments clothed skin lord"}, {"question": "did mankind become like God after they ate of the fruit of knowledge?", "answer": "The Lord God said, \"The man has now become like one of us, knowing good and evil. He must no be allowed to reach out his hand and take also from the tree of life and eat, and live forever. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:22", "keywords": "hand tree said eat evil god good allowed life knowing reach man lord live"}, {"question": "how did mankind become like God after they ate from the fruit of knowledge?", "answer": "Man became like God in knowing good and evil after they ate of the fruit of knowledge of good and evil.", "verse": "Genesis 3:22", "keywords": "fruit evil good god knowledge ate knowing man"}, {"question": "what was mankind not allowed to do after eating of the fruit of knowledge?", "answer": "Mankind was not allowed to eat from the fruit of the tree of life, and live forever.", "verse": "Genesis 3:22", "keywords": "fruit tree eat allowed mankind life live"}, {"question": "what is the tree of life?", "answer": "The tree of life is one of two trees that God placed in the middle of the garden of Eden. According to Genesis chapter 3 verse 22; if man reached out and ate from the tree of life he could live forever. ", "verse": "Genesis 3:22", "keywords": "trees man tree middle reached eden god life genesis garden verse ate placed chapter according live"}, {"question": "can you live forever if you eat from the tree of life?", "answer": "You live forever if you eat from the tree of life?", "verse": "Genesis 3:22", "keywords": "tree life eat live"}, {"question": "why did the Lord God banish Adam and Eve from the garden of Eden?", "answer": "God banished Adam and Eve from the garden of Eden because they ate from the tree of knowledge, whichhe forbid them from eating.", "verse": "Genesis 3:10-Genesis 3:22", "keywords": "tree adam eden god knowledge eve banished garden ate forbid eating"}, {"question": "what did Adam do after he was banished from the garden of Eden?", "answer": "After Adam was banished from he garden of Eden he worked the ground.", "verse": "Genesis 3:23", "keywords": "adam eden banished garden ground worked"}, {"question": "how is the garden of Eden protected after man was banished from it?", "answer": "God placed cherubim and a flaming sword on the east side of the garden.", "verse": "Genesis 3:23", "keywords": "god flaming sword garden cherubim placed east"}, {"question": "are there angels protecting the garden of Eden?", "answer": "God placed cherubim and a flaming sword on the east side of the garden.", "verse": "Genesis 3:24", "keywords": "god flaming sword garden cherubim placed east"}, {"question": "what is protecting the garden of Eden now?", "answer": "God placed cherubim and a flaming sword on the east side of the garden.", "verse": "Genesis 3:24", "keywords": "god flaming sword garden cherubim placed east"}, {"question": "who was Adam's first born son?", "answer": "Adam and Eve's first born was Cain.", "verse": "Genesis 4:1", "keywords": "born eve cain adam"}, {"question": "who was Eve's first born son?", "answer": "Adam and Eve's first born was Cain.", "verse": "Genesis 4:1", "keywords": "born eve cain adam"}, {"question": "what did Eve say when she gave birth to Cain?", "answer": "After giving birth to Cain Eve said, \"With the help of the lord I have brought forth a man.\"", "verse": "Genesis 4:1", "keywords": "brought said eve cain giving man birth help lord"}, {"question": "who was Adam's second born son?", "answer": "Adam and Eve's first born was Abel.", "verse": "Genesis 4:2", "keywords": "born abel eve adam"}, {"question": "who was Eve's first born son?", "answer": "Adam and Eve's first born was Abel.", "verse": "Genesis 4:2", "keywords": "born abel eve adam"}, {"question": "what did Abel do for work?", "answer": "Abel was a shepherd so he kept flocks.", "verse": "Genesis 4:2", "keywords": "shepherd kept abel flocks"}, {"question": "what did Cain do for work?", "answer": "Cain was farmer so he worked the soil.", "verse": "Genesis 4:2", "keywords": "soil worked cain farmer"}, {"question": "is Cain older than Abel?", "answer": "Cain wa born first to Adam and Eve, afterward Abel was born.", "verse": "Genesis 4:1-Genesis 4:2", "keywords": "born adam abel eve cain wa"}, {"question": "is Abel younger than Cain?", "answer": "Cain wa born first to Adam and Eve, afterward Abel was born.", "verse": "Genesis 4:1-Genesis 4:2", "keywords": "born adam abel eve cain wa"}, {"question": "what did Cain and Abel do for work?", "answer": "Cain was a farmer so he worked the soil, Abel was a shepherd so he kept flocks.", "verse": "Genesis 4:2", "keywords": "flocks farmer soil abel shepherd cain kept worked"}, {"question": "what did Cain bring to God as an offering?", "answer": "Cain brought some fruits from the soil as an offering to God.", "verse": "Genesis 4:3", "keywords": "brought soil god offering fruits cain"}, {"question": "what did Abel bring to God as an offering?", "answer": "Abel brought some fat portions from the firstborn of the flock.", "verse": "Genesis 4:4", "keywords": "brought firstborn abel fat portions flock"}, {"question": "Who's offering did God see with favor, Cain or Abel?", "answer": "God saw Abel's offering of fat from the firstborn of his flock with favor.", "verse": "Genesis 4:4", "keywords": "firstborn god fat abel offering favor saw flock"}, {"question": "Did the Lord God see Abel's offering with favor?", "answer": "God saw Abel's offering of fat from the firstborn of his flock with favor.", "verse": "Genesis 4:4", "keywords": "firstborn god fat abel offering favor saw flock"}, {"question": "Did the Lord God see Cain's offering with favor?", "answer": "God did not see Cain's offering of fruit from the ground with favor.", "verse": "Genesis 4:5", "keywords": "fruit god offering ground cain favor"}, {"question": "Why did Cain become angry after giving God his offering?", "answer": "Cain became very after giving God his offering of fruit because the Lord saw Abel's offering with favor and not his.", "verse": "Genesis 4:4-Genesis 4:5", "keywords": "fruit god abel offering giving cain favor saw lord"}, {"question": "What was Cain's reaction after God did not see his offering with favor?", "answer": "Cain became angry, and his face was downcast.", "verse": "Genesis 4:5", "keywords": "downcast cain angry face"}, {"question": "What did God say to Cain became angry?", "answer": "When Cain became angry, he asked him \"Why are you angry? Why is your face downcast?", "verse": "Genesis 4:6", "keywords": "asked face angry cain downcast"}, {"question": "How could Cain's offering be accepted before God?", "answer": "If Cain does what is right, he will be accepted.", "verse": "Genesis 4:7", "keywords": "accepted cain right"}, {"question": "Does God want us to do what is right?", "answer": "God wants us to do what is right, no bad deed is acceptable before his eyes.", "verse": "Genesis 4:7", "keywords": "god wants eyes bad acceptable right deed"}, {"question": "What happens if you do what is wrong?", "answer": "To those who do wrong, sin waits for them, sin wants to rule over them.", "verse": "Genesis 4:7", "keywords": "rule wrong sin wants waits"}, {"question": "Can sin consume someone life?", "answer": "Sin wishes to rule over you, always waiting at your door.", "verse": "Genesis 4:7", "keywords": "rule sin wishes waiting door"}, {"question": "How did Cain kill Abel?", "answer": "Cain said to Abel, \"Let's go out to the field\", while they were in the field Cain killed his brother.", "verse": "Genesis 4:8", "keywords": "said abel let killed brother field cain"}, {"question": "Did Cain kill Abel?", "answer": "While the brothers where out in the field, Cain attacked and killed Abel.", "verse": "Genesis 4:8", "keywords": "brothers abel killed attacked cain field"}, {"question": "What did Cain reply to the Lord God asked him where his brother able was?", "answer": "Cain replied to the Lord, \"Id don't know, am I my brothers keeper?\"", "verse": "Genesis 4:9", "keywords": "brothers keeper know replied cain d lord"}, {"question": "What did the Lord say about Able's death after he was murdered by Cain?", "answer": "The Lord God said to Cain, \"Listen! Your brother's blood cries out to me from the ground.\"", "verse": "Genesis 4:10", "keywords": "said god brother ground cain blood listen cries lord"}, {"question": "Was Cain placed under a curse for murdering his brother Abel?", "answer": "God placed Cain under a curse for murdering his brother Abel, which would drive him from the land.", "verse": "Genesis 4:11", "keywords": "land murdering drive god abel curse brother cain placed"}, {"question": "What was Cain curse for killing his brother Abel?", "answer": "Cain was driven from the land, it would no longer yield crops for him. He would be a restless wanderer on the earth", "verse": "Genesis 4:11-Genesis 4:12", "keywords": "driven yield wanderer land crops restless earth cain"}, {"question": "Was Cain afraid of the curse God placed on him?", "answer": "Cain was afraid of being driven from the land, and hidden from God's presence. He was afraid of being killed by whoever found him. ", "verse": "Genesis 4:13-Genesis 4-14", "keywords": "driven land god killed presence hidden cain afraid found"}, {"question": "Did God protect Cain from being murdered?", "answer": "God place a mark on Cain, and declared that anyone who killed Cain would suffer vengeance seven times over. ", "verse": "Genesis 4:15", "keywords": "mark times suffer declared vengeance god place killed cain"}, {"question": "Was Cain no longer in the Lord's presence?", "answer": "After murdering his brother Abel, Cain went out of the Lord's presence and lived in the land of Nod.", "verse": "Genesis 4:13-Genesis4:16", "keywords": "nod land murdering abel lived went brother presence cain lord"}, {"question": "Where did Cain live after he murdered his brother Abel?", "answer": "After murdering his brother Abel and going out of the Lord's presence Cain lived in the land of Nod, east of Eden. ", "verse": "Genesis 4:16", "keywords": "nod land murdering eden abel lived brother presence cain going east lord"}, {"question": "What was the name of Cain's first born son?", "answer": "Cain first born son was named Enoch.", "verse": "Genesis 4:17", "keywords": "born son enoch cain named"}, {"question": "What did Cain do after he left because murdered his bother Abel?", "answer": "Cain built a city and named it after his son Enoch.", "verse": "Genesis 4:17", "keywords": "son built enoch cain city named"}, {"question": "Did Cain build a city?", "answer": "Cain built a city and named it after his son Enoch.", "verse": "Genesis 4:17", "keywords": "son built enoch cain city named"}, {"question": "What was the name of Enoch son?", "answer": "Enoch's son was named Irad.", "verse": "Genesis 4:18", "keywords": "enoch irad named son"}, {"question": "What was the name of Irad son?", "answer": "Irad's son was named Mehujael.", "verse": "Genesis 4:18", "keywords": "irad named son mehujael"}, {"question": "What was the name of Mehujael's son?", "answer": "Mehujael's son was named Methushael.", "verse": "Genesis 4:18", "keywords": "mehujael named son methushael"}, {"question": "What was the name of Methushael's son?", "answer": "Methushael's son was named Lamech.", "verse": "Genesis 4:18", "keywords": "lamech methushael named son"}, {"question": "How many wives did Lamech have?", "answer": "Lamech had two wives, one was named Adah and the other was named Zillah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:19", "keywords": "zillah wives lamech named adah"}, {"question": "Who was Adah?", "answer": "Adah was one of Lamech's wives, the other was Zillah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:19", "keywords": "lamech wives adah zillah"}, {"question": "Who was Zillah?", "answer": "Zillad was one of Lamech's wives, the other was Adah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:19", "keywords": "lamech wives adah zillad"}, {"question": "Who was Jabal?", "answer": "Jabal was one of two sons Lamech had with Adah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:20", "keywords": "sons lamech jabal adah"}, {"question": "Who was Jabal's mother?", "answer": "Jabal's mother was Adah, and his father was Lamech.", "verse": "Genesis 4:20", "keywords": "father adah lamech mother jabal"}, {"question": "Who was Jabal's father?", "answer": "Jabal's mother was Adah, and his father was Lamech.", "verse": "Genesis 4:20", "keywords": "father adah lamech mother jabal"}, {"question": "Who are the descendants of Jabal? ", "answer": "The descendants of Jabal are the people known for living in tents and raising livestock.", "verse": "Genesis 4:20", "keywords": "known raising livestock living tents people jabal descendants"}, {"question": "Who was Jubal?", "answer": "Jubal was one of two sons Lamech had with Adah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:21", "keywords": "sons lamech jubal adah"}, {"question": "Who was Jubal's mother?", "answer": "Jubal's mother was Adah, and his father was Lamech.", "verse": "Genesis 4:21", "keywords": "father lamech jubal mother adah"}, {"question": "Who was Jubal's father?", "answer": "Jubal's mother was Adah, and his father was Lamech.", "verse": "Genesis 4:21", "keywords": "father lamech jubal mother adah"}, {"question": "Who are the descendants of Jubal? ", "answer": "The descendants of Jubal are the people known for playing stringed instruments and pipes.", "verse": "Genesis 4:21", "keywords": "known stringed instruments pipes playing people jubal descendants"}, {"question": "Did Adah have any children?", "answer": "Adah had two sons, Jabal and Jubal.", "verse": "Genesis 4:20-Genesis4:21", "keywords": "sons jabal jubal adah"}, {"question": "Did Zillah have any children?", "answer": "Lamech had two children with Zillah, a son named Tubal-Cain and a daugther named Naamah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:22", "keywords": "tubal naamah zillah son lamech children daugther cain named"}, {"question": "Who was Tubal-Cain?", "answer": "Tubal-Cain was the son Lamech with Zillah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:22", "keywords": "tubal zillah son lamech cain"}, {"question": "What was Tubal-Cain known for?", "answer": "Tubal-Cain was known for forging all kinds of tools out of Bronze and Iron.", "verse": "Genesis 4:22", "keywords": "known tubal iron tools cain bronze forging kinds"}, {"question": "Did Tubal-Cain have any siblings?", "answer": "Tubal-Cain had a sister named Naamah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:22", "keywords": "tubal naamah sister cain named"}, {"question": "Did Tubal-Cain have a sister?", "answer": "Tubal-Cain had a sister named Naamah.", "verse": "Genesis 4:22", "keywords": "tubal naamah sister cain named"}, {"question": "Did Lamech kill a someone?", "answer": "Lamech killed a young man for injuring him.", "verse": "Genesis 4:23", "keywords": "killed lamech young injuring man"}, {"question": "Why did Lamech kill someone?", "answer": "Lamech killed a young man because the man injured him.", "verse": "Genesis 4:23", "keywords": "injured killed lamech young man"}, {"question": "Did Lamech want to be avenged if he was killed?", "answer": "Lamech wanted to be avenged seventy times compared to the seven times God decreed over Cain.", "verse": "Genesis 4:24", "keywords": "times decreed god lamech cain wanted compared avenged"}, {"question": "Who is Seth?", "answer": "Seth is Adam's third son.", "verse": "Genesis 4:25", "keywords": "seth son adam"}, {"question": "Did Seth have children?", "answer": "Seth had a son, he named him Enosh.", "verse": "Genesis 4:26, Genesis 5:6", "keywords": "seth named son"}, {"question": "Who is Enosh?", "answer": "Enosh is the son of Seth.", "verse": "Genesis 4:26, Genesis 5:6", "keywords": "son seth enosh"}, {"question": "When did people begin to call on the name of the Lord?", "answer": "During the time of Enosh's life, people began to call on God.", "verse": "Genesis 4:26", "keywords": "began god life time people enosh"}, {"question": "Why do we say \"Mankind\"?", "answer": "When God created humans he called them \"Mankind.", "verse": "Genesis 5:2", "keywords": "god called mankind created humans"}, {"question": "Did God name humans \"Mankind\"?", "answer": "When God created humans he called them \"Mankind.", "verse": "Genesis 5:2", "keywords": "god called mankind created humans"}, {"question": "At what age did Adam have Seth?", "answer": "Seth was born when Adam was 120 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:3", "keywords": "born old adam seth years"}, {"question": "How many years did Adam live after he had Seth?", "answer": "Adam lived an additional 800 years after he had Seth.", "verse": "Genesis 5:4", "keywords": "adam seth lived years additional"}, {"question": "Did Adam have more children after he had Seth?", "answer": "Adam did have more children after he had Seth.", "verse": "Genesis 5:4", "keywords": "children seth adam"}, {"question": "How many years did Adam live?", "answer": "Adam lived a total of 930 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:5", "keywords": "years lived total adam"}, {"question": "At what age did Adam die?", "answer": "Adam died at the age of 930 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:5", "keywords": "age died old adam years"}, {"question": "At what age did Seth have Enosh?", "answer": "Enosh was born when Seth was 105 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:6", "keywords": "born old seth years enosh"}, {"question": "How many years did Seth live after he had Enosh?", "answer": "Seth lived an additional 807 years after he had Enosh.", "verse": "Genesis 5:7", "keywords": "seth lived years additional enosh"}, {"question": "Did Seth have more children after Enosh?", "answer": "Seth did have more children after Enosh.", "verse": "Genesis 5:7", "keywords": "children seth enosh"}, {"question": "How many years did Seth live", "answer": "Seth lived a total of 912 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:8", "keywords": "years seth lived total"}, {"question": "At what age did Seth die?", "answer": "Seth died at the age of 912 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:8", "keywords": "age died old seth years"}, {"question": "At what age did Enosh have Kenan?", "answer": "Kenan was born when Enosh was 90 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:9", "keywords": "born old kenan years enosh"}, {"question": "How many years did Enosh live after he had Kenan?", "answer": "Enosh lived an additional 815 years after he had Kenan.", "verse": "Genesis 5:10", "keywords": "kenan lived years additional enosh"}, {"question": "Did Enosh have more children after Kenan?", "answer": "Enosh did have more children after Kenan.", "verse": "Genesis 5:10", "keywords": "children kenan enosh"}, {"question": "How many years did Enosh live?", "answer": "Enosh lived a total of 905 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:11", "keywords": "years lived enosh total"}, {"question": "At what age did Enosh die?", "answer": "Enosh died at the age of 905 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:11", "keywords": "age died old years enosh"}, {"question": "At what age did Kenan have Mahalalel?", "answer": "Mahalalel was born when Kenan was 70 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:12", "keywords": "born old mahalalel kenan years"}, {"question": "How many years did Kenan live after he had Mahalalel?", "answer": "Kenan lived an additional 840 years after he had Mahalalel.", "verse": "Genesis 5:13", "keywords": "mahalalel kenan lived years additional"}, {"question": "Did Kenan have more children after Mahalalel?", "answer": "Kenan did have more children after Mahalalel.", "verse": "Genesis 5:13", "keywords": "children kenan mahalalel"}, {"question": "How many years did Kenan live?", "answer": "Kenan lived a total of 910 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:14", "keywords": "years kenan lived total"}, {"question": "At what age did Kenan die?", "answer": "Kenan died at the age of 905 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:14", "keywords": "age died old kenan years"}, {"question": "At what age did Mahalalel have Jared?", "answer": "Jared was born when Kenan was 65 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:15", "keywords": "born old kenan jared years"}, {"question": "How many years did Mahalalel live after he had Jared?", "answer": "Mahalalel lived an additional 830 years after he had Jared.", "verse": "Genesis 5:16", "keywords": "mahalalel jared lived years additional"}, {"question": "Did Mahalalel have more children after Jared?", "answer": "Mahalalel did have more children after Jared.", "verse": "Genesis 5:16", "keywords": "mahalalel children jared"}, {"question": "How many years did Mahalalel live?", "answer": "Mahalalel lived a total of 895 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:17", "keywords": "mahalalel lived total years"}, {"question": "At what age did Mahalalel die?", "answer": "Mahalalel died at the age of 895 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:17", "keywords": "age died old mahalalel years"}, {"question": "At what age did Jared have Enoch?", "answer": "Enoch was born when Jared was 162 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:18", "keywords": "born old jared years enoch"}, {"question": "How many years did Jared live after he had Enoch?", "answer": "Jared lived an additional 800 years after he had Enoch.", "verse": "Genesis 5:19", "keywords": "jared lived years enoch additional"}, {"question": "Did Jared have more children after Enoch?", "answer": "Jared did have more children after Enoch.", "verse": "Genesis 5:19", "keywords": "enoch children jared"}, {"question": "How many years did Jared live?", "answer": "Jared lived a total of 962 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:20", "keywords": "years jared lived total"}, {"question": "At what age did Jared die?", "answer": "Mahalalel died at the age of 962 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:20", "keywords": "age died old mahalalel years"}, {"question": "At what age did Enoch have Methuselah?", "answer": "Methuselah was born when Enoch was 65 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:21", "keywords": "born old years enoch methuselah"}, {"question": "How many years did Enoch live after he had Methuselah?", "answer": "Enoch did not die, he walked faithfully with God an additional 300 years after he had Methuselah, then God took him without seeing death.", "verse": "Genesis 5:22, Genesis 5:24, Hebrews 11:5", "keywords": "die death took seeing god years enoch walked additional methuselah"}, {"question": "Did Enoch have more children after Methuselah?", "answer": "Enoch did have more children after Methuselah.", "verse": "Genesis 5:22", "keywords": "enoch children methuselah"}, {"question": "How many years did Enoch live?", "answer": "Enoch lived a total of 365 years before God took him.", "verse": "Genesis 5:23", "keywords": "took total god lived years enoch"}, {"question": "At what age did Enoch die?", "answer": "Enoch did not die, he lived 365 years before God took him without seeing death.", "verse": "Genesis 5:23-Genesis 5:24, Hebrews 11:5", "keywords": "die death took seeing god lived years enoch"}, {"question": "Who walked faithfully with God?", "answer": "Enoch walked faithfully with God, because of that God took him.", "verse": "Genesis 5:24", "keywords": "enoch god walked took"}, {"question": "Why did God take Enoch?", "answer": "God took Enoch because he walked faithfully in God's eyes.", "verse": "Genesis 5:24", "keywords": "took god eyes enoch walked"}, {"question": "At what age did Methuselah have Lamech?", "answer": "Lamech was born when Methuselah was 187 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:25", "keywords": "born old years lamech methuselah"}, {"question": "how many years did Methuselah live after he had Lamech?", "answer": "Methuselah lived an additional 782 years after he had Lamech.", "verse": "Genesis 5:26", "keywords": "lived years lamech additional methuselah"}, {"question": "did Methuselah have mare children after Lamech?", "answer": "Methuselah did have more children after he had Lamech.", "verse": "Genesis 5:26", "keywords": "lamech methuselah children"}, {"question": "How many years did Methuselah live?", "answer": "Methuselah lived a total of 969 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:27", "keywords": "methuselah lived total years"}, {"question": "At what age did Methuselah die?", "answer": "Methuselah died at the age of 962 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:27", "keywords": "age died old years methuselah"}, {"question": "At what age did Lamech have Noah?", "answer": "Noah was born when Lamech was 182 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:28", "keywords": "born old years lamech noah"}, {"question": "What did Lamech say his son Noah would do?", "answer": "Lamech said his son Noah, \"... would confront us in the labor and toil of our hands caused by the ground the Lord has cursed.\" ", "verse": "Genesis 5:29", "keywords": "caused said toil son cursed lamech confront noah ground hands labor lord"}, {"question": "what does it mean that Noah would \"confront\" in the labor and toil his father Lamech declared?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "how many years did Lamech live after he had Noah?", "answer": "Lamech lived an additional 595 years after he had Noah.", "verse": "Genesis 5:30", "keywords": "lived years lamech noah additional"}, {"question": "did Lamech have mare children after Noah?", "answer": "Lamech did have more children after he had Noah.", "verse": "Genesis 5:30", "keywords": "lamech children noah"}, {"question": "How many years did Lamech live?", "answer": "Lamech lived a total of 777 years.", "verse": "Genesis 5:31", "keywords": "lamech years lived total"}, {"question": "At what age did Lamech die?", "answer": "Lamech died at the age of 777 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:31", "keywords": "age died old years lamech"}, {"question": "At what age did Noah have his sons?", "answer": "Shem, Ham and Japheth were born when Lamech was 500 years old.", "verse": "Genesis 5:32", "keywords": "born japheth old shem ham years lamech"}, {"question": "what were the names of Noah's sons?", "answer": "Shem, Ham and Japheth were Noah's sons in the book of Genesis.", "verse": "Genesis 5:32, Genesis 6:10", "keywords": "japheth shem ham book sons genesis noah"}, {"question": "who are Shem, Ham and Japheth in the Book of Genesis?", "answer": "They are the Sons of Noah.", "verse": "Genesis 5:32, Genesis 6:10", "keywords": "sons noah"}, {"question": "what did the sons of God do to the daughters of humans?", "answer": "The sons of God took any of the women they choose, and marry them.", "verse": "Genesis 6:1-Genesis 6:2", "keywords": "took god sons marry women choose"}, {"question": "why did the sons of God take and marry the daughters of humans?", "answer": "The sons of God saw that women were beautiful, so they took and marry which ever they choose.", "verse": "Genesis 6:1-Genesis 6:2", "keywords": "beautiful took god sons marry women saw choose"}, {"question": "who are the sons of God?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "who are the daughters of humans?", "answer": "In the book of Genesis, when humans started to populate the world, daughters were born to them.", "verse": "Genesis 6:1", "keywords": "world daughters born populate book genesis started humans"}, {"question": "did God limit humans lifespan?", "answer": "God declared that mankind lifespan would be 120 years.", "verse": "Genesis 6:3", "keywords": "lifespan declared god years mankind"}, {"question": "why did God limit humans lifespan", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "does God still contend with humankind?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "what does it mean that God's spirit will not contend with humans forever?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "when were the Nephilim on earth?", "answer": "The Nephilim where on earth in the days of Noah and can be found in the days of Moses.", "verse": "Genesis 6:4", "keywords": "moses earth days noah nephilim found"}, {"question": "what are Nephilim?", "answer": "Nephilim are famous and power giants of ancient times. They were on the earth in the days of Noah and in the days of Moses. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:4, Numbers 13:33", "keywords": "times giants moses famous earth days power noah nephilim ancient"}, {"question": "did giants exist?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "are people naturally evil?", "answer": "The human heart will lean to evil and wickedness, continuously.", "verse": "Genesis 6:5", "keywords": "human evil lean heart wickedness"}, {"question": "what is the human heart?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "what are the thoughts of the human heart?", "answer": "Without God the thoughts of the human heart are only evil all the time.", "verse": "Genesis 6:5", "keywords": "human thoughts evil god time heart"}, {"question": "can the human race be wicked?", "answer": "Without God the human race can be greatly wicked, and always thinking of evil things?", "verse": "Genesis 6:5", "keywords": "human wicked evil god race things thinking"}, {"question": "what is evil?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "does God regret things?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "what is God's regret?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "can God's heart be troubled?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Verse NOT FOUND", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "what did God feel when he saw mankind's wickedness?", "answer": "God's heart was deeply troubled because of how great humans's wickedness was.", "verse": "Genesis 6:6", "keywords": "god wickedness heart troubled humans great"}, {"question": "why did God wipe all mankind, the animals that walk the ground, and the birds?", "answer": "Because of how great mankind wickedness was, God wiped away all things that moved on the ground and flew through the air, except Noah and his family. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:5-Genesis 6:8", "keywords": "air god moved family mankind wickedness noah wiped ground flew things great"}, {"question": "who was the only one that found favor when God was going to destroy the world with a flood?", "answer": "Noah and his family were the only ones that found favor in God's eyes when the world was going to be destroyed. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:7-Genesis 6:8, Genesis 7:1", "keywords": "ones world god family eyes destroyed noah favor going found"}, {"question": "why did Noah find favor in God's eyes?", "answer": "Noah was a righteous man, blameless among the people of his time who walked with God.", "verse": "Genesis 6:9, Genesis 7:1", "keywords": "righteous god blameless noah walked time people man"}, {"question": "what were people like in Noah's time?", "answer": "The world was corrupted, full of violence, everything they did, and all the thoughts in people's hearts were wicked all the time. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:5, Genesis 6:11-Genesis 6:12", "keywords": "world thoughts hearts wicked violence corrupted time people"}, {"question": "how bad can mankind get?", "answer": "Without God, the world can be full of perversion, violence, with everything people think and do be wicked all time.", "verse": "Genesis 6:5, Genesis 6:11-Genesis 6:12", "keywords": "world think wicked god violence perversion time people"}, {"question": "who's fault was it that the earth wicked in Noah's time?", "answer": "The people filled the earth with wickedness and violence, and because of that God destroyed the earth.", "verse": "Genesis 6:11-Genesis 6:13", "keywords": "filled violence god earth destroyed people wickedness"}, {"question": "what did God command Noah to build?", "answer": "God commanded Noah to build an ark.", "verse": "Genesis 6:14", "keywords": "ark god commanded noah build"}, {"question": "how was Noah suppose to build the ark?", "answer": "The ark was suppose to be built using gopherwood (cypress in the NIV). It was to have rooms coated inside and out with pitch. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:14", "keywords": "ark coated pitch built rooms gopherwood cypress niv suppose"}, {"question": "what kind of wood was Noah suppose to use to build the ark?", "answer": "The hebrew word is transliterated as gopherwood, which is only known and used once in original scripture.  Different translations use timber, cypress, lumber, cedar, etc.", "verse": "Genesis 6:14", "keywords": "known different use hebrew timber cedar transliterated scripture gopherwood translations cypress original word lumber"}, {"question": "what is gopher wood?", "answer": "Gopher is the term transliterated from the original scriptures to describe the type of wood Noah was to use to build the ark. It is only known and used once. Different translations use timber, cypress, lumber, cedar, etc. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:14", "keywords": "different use ark term build type wood timber cedar noah translations cypress original scriptures lumber known describe transliterated gopher"}, {"question": "what is pitch?", "answer": "Pitch coating used to in buildings and vessels. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:14", "keywords": "coating vessels buildings pitch"}, {"question": "what are the measurements of Noah's ark?", "answer": "Noah's ark was 300 cubits long, 50 cubits wide, and 30 cubits high.", "verse": "Genesis 6:15", "keywords": "long ark high noah cubits wide"}, {"question": "How long was Noah's ark?", "answer": "Noah's ark was 300 cubits long.", "verse": "Genesis 6:15", "keywords": "long noah ark cubits"}, {"question": "How wide was Noah's ark?", "answer": "Noah's ark was 50 cubits wide.", "verse": "Genesis 6:15", "keywords": "noah ark wide cubits"}, {"question": "How tall was Noah's ark?", "answer": "Noah's ark was 30 cubits tall.", "verse": "Genesis 6:15", "keywords": "noah ark cubits tall"}, {"question": "how long is a cubit?", "answer": "There are different lengths for a cubit in the ancient world.  Generally a cubit the length from the elbow to the longest finger in the hand. ", "verse": "NO_VERSE", "keywords": "hand different world cubit finger lengths elbow longest ancient length"}, {"question": "how tall was the roof opening on Noah's ark?", "answer": "The roof opening was one cubit high all around.", "verse": "Genesis 6:16", "keywords": "high roof cubit opening"}, {"question": "where was the door opening on Noah's ark?", "answer": "The door was located on the side of the ark.", "verse": "Genesis 6:16", "keywords": "located door ark"}, {"question": "how many decks did Noah's ark have?", "answer": "The ark that Noah and his family built had three decks. Lower, middle, and upper decks.", "verse": "Genesis 6:16", "keywords": "upper ark middle decks family built noah lower"}, {"question": "how did God destroy the earth in Noah's time?", "answer": "God made it rain for 40 days and 40 nights. He brought the flood waters to destroy everything that lived on the earth.", "verse": "Genesis 6:17, Genesis 7:4, Genesis 7:12, Genesis 7:14", "keywords": "brought god nights waters lived earth rain days flood destroy"}, {"question": "who where the people saved from the flood?", "answer": "Noah, his wife, his sons, and their wives were the only people saved from the flood. They entered the ark during the great flood.", "verse": "Genesis 6:18, Genesis 7:1, Genesis 7:7, Genesis 7:13", "keywords": "ark wife great wives sons noah flood saved people entered"}, {"question": "what animals did Noah bring into the ark?", "answer": "God commanded Noah to bring into the ark a pair of every kind of bird and animal the moves along the ground according to their kinds. He had to bring 7 pairs of clean animals and birds, and one pair of unclean animals and birds.  A pair is made up of a male and female. ", "verse": "Genesis 6:19-Genesis 6:20, Genesis 7:8-Genesis 7:9, Genesis 7:14, Genesis 7:15", "note": "Genesis 7:2 gives a different number then 6:19,6:20", "keywords": "ark bird kind clean kinds birds noah male according moves commanded bring ground female animals animal god pairs unclean pair"}, {"question": "what did Noah, his family, and all the animals eat while inside the ark?", "answer": "God commanded Noah to take and store all the food the animals and his family needed to eat.", "verse": "Genesis 6:20-Genesis 6:21", "keywords": "animals eat needed god food family commanded noah store"}, {"question": "how did Noah respond to God's commands of building the ark, taking the animals and storing food?", "answer": "Noah did everything just as God commanded.", "verse": "Genesis 6:14-Genesis 6:16, Genesis 6:19-Genesis 6:22, Genesis 7:5", "keywords": "commanded noah god"}, {"question": "how early did God warn Noah about the rains and floodwaters?", "answer": "The bible only specifies that God commanded Noah to build the ark and how he would destroy the world. Then warned him seven days before the rains came.", "verse": "Genesis 7:4, Genesis 7:10", "keywords": "world ark god rains commanded bible noah days specifies came build destroy warned"}, {"question": "how long did it rain when God sent the floodwaters in Noah's time?", "answer": "It rained for 40 days and 40 nights when God sent the great flood in Noah's time.", "verse": "Genesis 7:4, Genesis 7:12, Genesis 7:14", "keywords": "sent nights god days noah time flood rained great"}, {"question": "how old was Noah when God flooded the world?", "answer": "Noah was 600 years, 2 months and 7 days old when God sent the great flood. ", "verse": "Genesis 7:6", "keywords": "old sent god months years days noah flood great"}, {"question": "where did the great flood come from?", "answer": "God sent the great flood to destroy the world. God opened up the great waters from the sky, and the great waters from under the ground to flood the earth. ", "verse": "Genesis 7:11, Genesis 8:2", "keywords": "world sent sky god waters earth ground flood opened destroy great"}, {"question": "who closed the ark?", "answer": "After all the animals and Noah and his family entered the ark, God closed them in.", "verse": "Genesis 7:16", "keywords": "animals ark god family noah closed entered"}, {"question": "for how long did the flood waters kept rising?", "answer": "the waters of the great flood kept rising for 40 days.", "verse": "Genesis 7:17, Genesis 7:19, Genesis 6:18, Genesis 7:1, Genesis 7:7, Genesis 7:13", "keywords": "waters days flood rising kept great"}, {"question": "did the ark float?", "answer": "The flood waters rose and lifted the ark. The ark floated to the surface of the water.", "verse": "Genesis 7:17-Genesis 7:18", "keywords": "lifted rose ark floated surface waters water flood"}, {"question": "did the flood cover everything?", "answer": "The flood was so great that it covered even the highest mountains. It covered the mountains more than (estimated) 20 feet.", "verse": "{} 7:17-{} 7:20", "keywords": "feet mountains flood estimated covered highest great"}, {"question": "did everything outside the ark die during the great flood?", "answer": "Everything that walked on the ground and flew in the sky that was not inside the ark died in the great flood.", "verse": "Genesis 7:21-Genesis 7:23", "keywords": "died ark sky walked ground flood flew great"}, {"question": "how long did flood last?", "answer": "During the great flood, it rained for 40 day and 40 nights and the world was flooded 150 days.", "verse": "Genesis 7:4, Genesis 7:12, Genesis 7:14, Genesis 7:24, Genesis 8:3", "keywords": "world nights day days flood flooded rained great"}, {"question": "did God ever forget?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Genesis 8:1", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "how did God stop the flood?", "answer": "God sent a wind over all the earth, and closed the floodgates in the heavens and the deep, and stopped the rains. The waters slowly fell back. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:1-Genesis 8:3", "keywords": "floodgates fell sent wind god waters earth rains deep closed stopped heavens"}, {"question": "where did Noah's ark end up?", "answer": "When the waters of the great flood subsided, the ark ended up on the mountains of Ararat.", "verse": "Genesis 8:4", "keywords": "ark ararat waters subsided ended mountains flood great"}, {"question": "where are the mountains of Ararat located?", "answer": "The mountains of Ararat are located in Turkey.", "verse": "Genesis 8:4", "keywords": "mountains located turkey ararat"}, {"question": "when did the ark finally rest on the mountains?", "answer": "The ark came to rest on the 17th day of the 7th month, on the year of the flood.", "verse": "Genesis 8:4", "keywords": "7th ark rest month year day 17th came flood"}, {"question": "after the Ararat mountains, when did the rest of the mountains become visible?", "answer": "The rest of the mountains became visible on the 1st day of the 10th month, on year of the flood.", "verse": "Genesis 8:5", "keywords": "10th rest 1st month year day mountains flood visible"}, {"question": "when did Noah look out of the ark?", "answer": "Noah looked out through a window after forty days.", "verse": "Genesis 8:6", "note": "Need to make sure that this verse refers to the forty days after it stopped raining.", "keywords": "days noah looked window"}, {"question": "what did Noah first sent out to find land?", "answer": "Noah sent out a raven to find land, but it kept flying back and forth.", "verse": "Genesis 8:7", "keywords": "raven land sent flying find noah kept"}, {"question": "what did Noah send out after the raven?", "answer": "After the raven, Noah sent out a dove to see if the waters had gone down.", "verse": "Genesis 8:8", "keywords": "raven sent waters dove gone noah"}, {"question": "what was the second animal noah sent out to look for land?", "answer": "The second animal Noah sent out to look for land was a dove.", "verse": "Genesis 8:8", "keywords": "land sent animal dove look noah second"}, {"question": "what were the animal that Noah sent out to look for land?", "answer": "Noah first sent out a raven, then he sent out a dove to look for land.", "verse": "Genesis 8:7-Genesis 8:8", "keywords": "raven land sent dove look noah"}, {"question": "how many times did Noah sent out the dove to look for land?", "answer": "Noah sent out the dove 3 times to look for land. The first time it did not find any land. The second time it found an olive tree. The third time it did not return. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:8-Genesis 8:12", "keywords": "tree times land sent dove find look noah olive time return second found"}, {"question": "what did the dove find the first time Noah sent it out to find land?", "answer": "The first time that Noah sent out the dove, it did not find anything?", "verse": "Genesis 8:8-Genesis 8:9", "keywords": "sent dove find noah time"}, {"question": "why did the dove not find anything the first time it went out?", "answer": "The dove could not find anywhere to rest the first time it went out, because everything was still covered by the floodwaters. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:9", "keywords": "rest dove find went time covered floodwaters"}, {"question": "how long did Noah wait, until he sent out the dove again after it returned?", "answer": "Noah waited 7 days before he sent out the dove again.", "verse": "Genesis 8:10, Genesis 8:12", "keywords": "waited sent dove days noah"}, {"question": "what did the dove find on the second time Noah sent it out?", "answer": "On the second time the dove was sent out, it found a an olive tree, which it took of a leaf and brought it back to Noah.", "verse": "Genesis 8:11", "keywords": "tree brought took sent dove leaf olive noah time second found"}, {"question": "how did Noah know that the flood waters were going down?", "answer": "The second time that the dove returned, it had a olive leaf it took from a tree. This is how Noah knew the floodwaters were going down. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:11", "keywords": "tree took dove leaf olive noah time going floodwaters second knew returned"}, {"question": "what happened to the dove on the third time Noah sent it out?", "answer": "On the third time that Noah sent out the dove, it did not return.", "verse": "Genesis 8:12", "keywords": "sent dove noah time return"}, {"question": "when did the floodwaters dry up from the earth?", "answer": "By the  1st day of the 1st month, on the year that Noah was 601 years old, Noah could see the dry land, and by the 27th day of the second month all the water from the great flood was completely gone. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:13-Genesis 8:14", "keywords": "month 1st old dry land gone year years day water noah 27th flood second great"}, {"question": "when did Noah come out of the ark?", "answer": "God commanded Noah, his family, and all the animals inside the ark to come out, after the waters had dried up. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:14-Genesis 8:19", "keywords": "animals ark dried god waters family commanded noah come"}, {"question": "what did Noah do after coming out of the ark?", "answer": "Noah built an altar for the Lord, and sacrificed some of the clean animals?", "verse": "Genesis 8:20", "keywords": "animals sacrificed built clean noah altar lord"}, {"question": "did Noah kill some of the animals he had in the ark?", "answer": "After everything came out of the ark, Noah sacrificed some of the clean animals and birds he had with him. He had 7 pairs of all the clean animals and birds, not just 1. ", "verse": "Genesis 7:2-Genesis 7:3, Genesis 8:20", "keywords": "animals ark sacrificed pairs clean noah came birds"}, {"question": "did God promise never to destroy the world again?", "answer": "God promised he would not curse the ground because of mankind's evil, or destroy every living thing as he did with the great flood again. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:21", "keywords": "great evil god mankind curse ground flood living promised destroy thing"}, {"question": "how early do people have evil in them?", "answer": "Mankind has evil thoughts in their hearts as early is childhood.", "verse": "Genesis 8:21", "keywords": "hearts thoughts childhood evil mankind early"}, {"question": "are kids evil?", "answer": "Evil is in the hearts of people as early as childhood.", "verse": "Genesis 8:21", "keywords": "childhood evil people hearts"}, {"question": "will the seasons ever end?", "answer": "As long as the earth exists, heat and cold,  seed-time and harvest, summer and winter, day and night will never end. That is what God All Mighty declared. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:22", "keywords": "summer cold heat winter declared end god night earth harvest day time seed exists"}, {"question": "can day time or night time ever end?", "answer": "As long as the earth exists, heat and cold,  seed-time and harvest, summer and winter, day and night will never end. That is what God All Mighty declared. ", "verse": "Genesis 8:22", "keywords": "summer cold heat winter declared end god night earth harvest day time seed exists"}, {"question": "are all the animals naturally afraid mankind?", "answer": "All the animals in the world naturally fear humans.", "verse": "Genesis 9:2", "keywords": "animals world humans fear"}, {"question": "can I eat meat that still blood in it?", "answer": "The answer is not found", "verse": "Genesis 9:4", "keywords": "found answer"}, {"question": "who is Jesus Christ?", "answer": "Jesus Christ is the Messiah.", "verse": "Mathews 1:1", "keywords": "christ messiah jesus"}]